<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="isarsu[at]sourceforge[dot]net">Arne Sutor</author>
        <title>The mission</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
		<section name="Our mission">
			<p>
				We are pleased to announce this Open Source project to support 
				all universities, institutes, institutes and students. 
				We separate our mission in two kind of activities: 
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Developers</li>
				<li>Users</li>
			</ul>
			<subsection name="Developers">
				<p>
					Developers are programmers that want to contribute building architecture, 
					APIs and reference implementation for OpenUSS. <br/>
					OpenUSS should be built component oriented with the newest software 
					technologies that available at the software market. It is also important 
					to use available Open Source Software in all parts of this system, because 
					we don't want to reinvent the wheel two times. <br/>
					For interested developers please look at the 
					<a href="team-list.html">developers'</a> page of this site.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Users">
				<p>
					Users are universities, institutes, institutes and students, which use 
					OpenUSS as their publishing and information center system (portal). <br/>
					They should have an easy system to deal with lectures, documents and exercises. 
					Besides the portal should be the communication center for all kind of such 
					organisation's members. Universities, institutes and intitutes which 
					don't have a capability to run the system can use the reference implementation 
					and outsource it to OpenUSS. This is important because many institutes don't 
					have the knowledge and a possibility to set up such a publishing system. 
					To all users please refer the <a href="users.html">users'</a> page of this site.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<p>
				We will offer this system as an Open Source Software. For the licence please look 
				at our <a href="license.html">license policy</a>. 
				The success of this system depends on all the developers' and users' activities.
			</p>
			<p>
				If you found an improvent please refer to your <a href="http://teamopenuss.uni-muenster.de/jira/browse/USS">Issue Tracking System Site</a> or <br/>
				just send us an email to <a href="mailto:openuss@e-learning.uni-muenster">OpenUSS Project Team</a>.
			</p>
		</section>
    </body>
</document>
