<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

    <properties>
     <author email="isarsu.AT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Arne Sutor</author>
        <author email="kstettner.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Kai Stettner</author>
        <author email="ronhaus.AT.users.DOT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Ron Haus</author>
        <title>Getting Started Guide</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
     <a name="top"/>
     
<section name="Overview">
      <p>
       In order to get your project up and running on Windows, please just follow the steps mentioned below.
 <ul>
        <li><a href="#java-install">Java 6 Installation and Configuration</a></li>
        <li><a href="#maven-install">Maven 2 Installation and Configuration</a></li>
        <li><a href="#firebird-install">Firebird 2.0 Installation and Configuration</a></li>
        <li><a href="#eclipse-download">Eclipse 3.2 Installation and Configuration</a></li>
            <li>
              <a href="#almost-finished">Finished?</a>
            </li>
 </ul>
     If anything goes wrong, please refer to the <a href="../troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting page</a>. If not reported yet, please let us know.
    </p>
</section>
     
     <a name="java-install"/>
    <section name="Java 6 Installation and Configuration">
   
   <p>The Java 6 JDK can be downloaded from the <a href="http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index.jsp" target="_blank">Sun Homepage</a>. Please set the following classpaths for windows:<br/>
   <ul>
     <li><code>JAVA_HOME</code> - The directory of the local JAVA-SDK installation.</li>
     <li><code>PATH</code> - Add the path to the <code>bin</code>-directory of your JAVA-SDK installation.</li>
   </ul>
    <p>(For testing issues just enter <code>java -version</code> resp. <code>javac</code> into your command shell.)</p>
   </p>
  </section>
  
  
  <a name="maven-install"/>
<section name="Maven 2 Installation and Configuration">
<p>
    Maven 2 can be downloaded from the <a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html" target="_blank">Maven 2 Site</a><br/>
    Unzip it into a specified directory, e.g. <code>C:\PathToMaven2</code>.
 </p>
   <p>
    Refer to the <strong>readme.txt</strong> in the root directory of your Maven 2 Installation.<br/>
    Please ensure that

 <ul>
   <li><code>M2_HOME</code> is set and is pointing to the correct Maven installation (type mvn --version into the command shell to test it)</li>
   <li>The Maven <code>bin</code>-directory is in your <code>PATH</code> variable</li>
 </ul>
 </p>
   <p>Create a folder of your choice where Maven can store its (local) repository. (e.g. <code>M2_HOME</code>/repository)<br/>
   Then add or check that the configuration entry of your <code>M2_HOME</code>/conf/settings.xml points to that repository folder. </p>
   <div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
  </section>
  
  <a name="firebird-install"/>  
        <section name="Firebird 2.0 Installation and Configuration">
   <p>
    Firebird 2.0 can be downloaded from the <a href="http://www.firebirdsql.org/" target="_blank">Firebird Site</a><br/>
    Please choose the installer method. This makes things easier for you. Just follow the onscreen instructions.
   </p>
   <p>
    A nice admin tool for firebird databases can be downloaded from the <a href="http://www.ibexpert.com/download.php" target="_blank">IBExpert Site</a><br/>
    Just install it using the onscreen instructions.
   </p>
   <p>
    OpenUSS requires two databases with the aliases: <code>openuss30</code> and <code>openuss30-test</code> (During the process of migration you also need the alias <code>openuss</code>).<br/>
    Either you download the pre-defined databases or you create new ones with the help of the hibernate schema exporter.    
   <ul>
     <li><code>openuss30</code> points to your main database for OpenUSS</li>
     <li><code>openuss30-test</code> points to your main test database for OpenUSS</li>
     <li><code>openuss</code> is just necessary for the migration: points to your old OpenUSS database (or something else)</li>
   </ul>
    The aliases specified above have to be defined in the <code>aliases.conf</code> file in your firebird installation folder.<br/>
    <code>openuss=D:\Path_to_your_databases\OPENUSS-30.FDB</code><br/>
    <code>openuss30=D:\Path_to_your_databases\OPENUSS-30.FDB</code><br/>
    <code>openuss30-test=D:\Path_to_your_databases\OPENUSS-30-TEST.FDB</code>
   </p>
   <p> 
    Afterwards you have to register the databases in the firebird database server via IBExpert.<br/>
    Just use the function "Register Database" using the following standard settings:
   <ul>
     <li>Server: Remote</li>
     <li>Server name: localhost</li>
     <li>Server version: Firebird 2.0</li>
     <li>Database file and alias: the according alias</li>
     <li>User name: sysdba</li>
     <li>Password: masterkey</li>
   </ul>
    The other settings should be left to the standard entries.
   </p>
   <div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
  </section>
  
  <a name="eclipse-download"/>
        <section name="Download Eclipse 3.2 Callisto">
   <p>
    Download the <a href="http://teamopenuss.uni-muenster.de/downloads/eclipse-3.2.zip">preconfigured eclipse version</a> and unzip it to your harddisk.
   </p>
   <p>
    After you have unzipped eclipse go to the <a href="http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/download" target="_blank">Exadel Studio Site</a> and download the free version <code>Exadel Studio 4.0</code>. 
    After the download please follow the onscreen instructions to install it.   </p>
      <p>
        Recommendation: If you use a computer with less than 1024MB memory, the usage of the eclipse distribution is quite uncomfortable.
        Instead you should download the normal <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">Eclipse 3.2 distribution</a>. If you choose to download the normal version you have to install Eclipse, define a new workspace and follow the instructions below:
        <ul>
          <li>Set the java compiler to 6.0</li>
          <li>Add <code>JDK 6</code> to the Eclipse setting "Java-Installed JREs"</li>
          <li>Add <code>m2_repo</code> to the "Ant_Runtime_Properties"</li>
          <li>Add <code>M2_REPO</code> to the "Java Build-Path Classpath"</li>
          <li>Install the plug-ins Web Standard Tools (WST) and J2EE Standard Tools (JST) from the Eclipse Update Site (Callisto)</li>
          <li>
            Install Subversive 1.1. from the Ecplise-Plugin-Site <a href="http://www.polarion.org/projects/subversive/download/1.1/update-site/"></a>
          </li>
          <li>Add to "Team-Ignored Ressources" the pattern "target"</li>
          <li>Register a new repository in the repository view of Eclipse with the URL <a href="https://openuss.svn.sourceforge.net/svnroot/openuss">https://openuss.svn.sourceforge.net/svnroot/openuss</a><br/>
            As authentication you have to use your sourceforge username and password.</li>
          <li>Check out the project "openuss-plexus" from the just included repository. </li>
          <li>Go back to the Java view of Eclipse and execute the Ant-Target "install w/o tests", which initiates the Maven-Build-Process, in the main build.xml</li>
          <li>
            Import the child projects of the main project out of the workspace (Import, don't copy them!)
          </li>
          <li>Define a new server (Apache Tomcat 5.5 from the project folder servers/tomcat) in the server view</li>
          <li>Add all projects on the server</li>
          <li>Start the server in the debug mode</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
   <div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
  </section>


      <a name="almost-finished"/>
      <section name="Finished?">
        <p>
          You have succefully completed the installation and configuration of OpenUSS if you see the start screen of OpenUSS<br/>
          after entering the URL <a href="http://localhost:8080/openuss-plexus">http://localhost:8080/openuss-plexus</a>.
          If this doesn't work, please refer to the previous sections or the troubleshooting page!        </p>
        <div align="right">
          <a href="#top">Go to the top.</a>
        </div>
      </section>
 
    </body>
</document>
