<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<document>

    <properties>
		<author email="isarsu[at]sourceforge[dot]net">Arne Sutor</author>
        <title>Sponsors</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="brought to you by">
        <a name="campussource"/>
		<h4>
			Campus Source
		</h4>
		<p>
			The Portal for Open Source Software for higher education. 
			CampusSource is supported by "Das Ministerium fuer Schule, 
			Wissenschaft und Forschung des Landes Nordrhein - Westfalen, Germany".
		</p>
		<p>
			View the <a href="http://www.campussource.de/">CampusSource homepage</a> for details.
		</p>
		<a name="ercis" />
		<h4>
			Ercis
		</h4>
		<p>
			The ERCIS - European Research Center for Information Systems - is a network 
			of scientists that conduct cooperative research in the field of integrated 
			information systems development and organizational design. For the first time, 
			core competencies in the discipline of information systems are interrelated 
			with issues in the field of computer science, business administration and 
			specific legal issues within an institutional framework. Thus, a holistic 
			view of information system development and organizational design issues can 
			be ensured.
			<br/>
			Due to its outstanding reputation in both research and teaching within the 
			field of information systems and business administration, the University of 
			Münster has been selected by the federal state of North Rhine-Westphalia to 
			found the European Research Center for Information Systems. Its objective 
			is to undertake joint research projects that span different disciplines and 
			countries, thus fostering research at a level that cannot be achieved by 
			individual go-it-alone projects. The exchange of researchers, such as PhD 
			students, lecturers or (associate) professors, is encouraged and cooperative 
			masters and doctoral programs are also part of the overall objective.
		</p>
		<p>
			View the <a href="http://www.ercis.de/">Ercis homepage</a> for details.
		</p>
		<a name="partner"/>
		<h4>
			<a name="partners">Partner Universities</a>
		</h4>
		<ul>
			<li><a href="http://www.htwk-leipzig.de/">Leipzig University of Applied Sciences</a></li>
			<li><a href="http://www.upn.mx/">National University of Pedagogy Mexico</a></li>
			<li><a href="http://www.stibanas.ac.id/">STIMIK Perbanas</a></li>
			<li><a href="http://www.ansteduniversity.org/">Ansted University</a></li>
		</ul>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>
