<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="isarsu[at]sourceforge[dot]net">Arne Sutor</author>
        <title>Training</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
		<a name="content"/>
		<section name="Content of the introduction trainings">
			<p>
				The training service of the E-Learning Competence Center consits of the following modules:
			</p>
			<ol>
				<li><b>Designing E-Learning Szenarios</b></li>
				<li><b>Communication and Cooperation in the World Wide Web</b></li>
				<li><b>Designing E-Learning Materials</b></li>
			</ol>
		<p>
			The trainings are taking place twice a semester, one at the beginning and the other at the end.
		</p>
		<subsection name="1. Designing E-Learning Szenarios">
			<p>
				In this course the participants will get an overview about the different 
				usage possibilities which E-Learning offers. On represantative examples you will 
				get trained on how E-Learning can be used in your everyday life at university.
				Along with didactic tips you will get hints on how teachers can offer a secure 
				access to their materials.Additionally you will get an introduction to the xlx System.
				With the xlx system theachers can offer electronic supported exercises along with theire 
				courses.
			</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="2. Communication and Cooperation in the World Wide Web">
			<p>
				Electronic communication and cooperation with students is taking the center stage of this course.
				The participants of the course are offered a possibillity on how to offer
				E-Learning materials with the plattform OpenUSS and on 
				how to communicate synchrone and assynchrone with your students.
				In the second part of the course you will get an overview on how to use the content management plattform
				HERBIE. With HERBIE students and teachers can work cooperative on science objects.
			</p>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="3. Designing E-Learning Materials">
			<p>
				Electronic materials offer multiple advantages for both teachers and students due 
				to the multimedia content.
				In this course the participants will learn how to use these adavantages on 
				different learning channels.Furthermore you will get informed on the actual overview
				on the judical site of how to design and use inoffensive materials.
			</p>
		</subsection>
		</section>
		<a name="contact"/>
		<section name="Contact Information for Consulting, Service and Training">
			<h4>
				Australia
			</h4>
			<p>
				<b><a href="http://www.atlassian.com/">Atlassian - Sydney (J2EE Experts)</a></b><br/>
				Email: sales[at]atlassian[dot]com<br/>
				Support: support[at]atlassian[dot]com<br/>
				General Inquiries: info[at]atlassian[dot]com
			</p>
			<p>
				Postal: Atlassian Software Services, Level 3, 342 Kent St Sydney, NSW 2000, Australia<br/>
				Phone: +61 (2) 9552 3826<br/>
				Fax: +61 (2) 9660 7442
				Urgent Engineer Call: +61 (416) 106 090 (use this number if you need to contact an engineer urgently)
			</p>
			<h4>
				Germany
			</h4>
			<p>
				<b><a href="http://www.wi.uni-muenster.de/aw">Institut fuer Wirtschaftsinformatik Lehrstuhl fuer Wirtschaftsinformatik und Controlling</a></b><br/>
				Dipl. Wirt.-Inform. Ingo Dueppe<br/>
				E-Mail: openuss[at]e-learning.uni-muenster[dot]de<br/>
				Leonardo-Campus 3, D-48149 Muenster
			</p>
			<p>
				<b>Plattformuebergreifende Beratungsleistungen für die Themen 
				- Controlling &amp; Steuerungssysteme - Prozessmodellierung - 
				Prozessmonitoring von E-Learning-Plattformen werden bereitgestellt von:<br/>
				<a href="http://www.horvath-partners.com">Horvath Customer Intelligence GmbH</a></b><br/>
				Ansprechpartner: Dipl.-Kfm. André Coners<br/>
				E-Mail: aconers@horvath-partners.com<br/>
				Mendelstr. 11, D-48149 Münster<br/>
				Phone: +49 (251) 980 1290<br/>
				Fax: +49 (251) 980 1299
			</p>
			<h4>
				Indonesia
			</h4>
			<p>
				<a href="http://www.stibanas.ac.id"><b>Stimik Perbanas</b></a><br/>
				Perbanas Building Unit II 3rd. floor, Jalan Perbanas Kuningan, Jakarta 12940, Indonesia <br/>
				Phone: +62 (0)21 5278788<br/>
				Fax: +62 (0)21 5278788
			</p>	
		</section>
    </body>
</document>
