<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="isarsu.AT.sourceforge.DOT.net">Arne Sutor</author>
        <title>Getting Started Guide</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
    	<a name="top"/>
	    <section name="Overview">
	    	<p>
	    		In order to get your project up and running, please just follow the steps mentioned below.
	    		<ul>
	    			<li><a href="#maven-install">Maven 2 Installation and Configuration</a></li>
	    			<li><a href="#firebird-install">Firebird Installation and Configuration</a></li>
	    			<li><a href="#eclipse-download">Download Eclipse 3.2 Callisto</a></li>
	    			<li><a href="maven-repo">Set up your Maven2 Repository</a></li>
	    		</ul>
	    		If anything goes wrong please refer to the <a href="../troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting page</a>. If not reported yet, please let us know.
	    	</p>
	    </section>
		<a name="maven-install"/>
        <section name="Maven 2 Installation and Configuration">
			<p>
				Maven 2 can be downloaded from the <a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html">Maven 2 Site</a><br/>
				Unzip it into a specified directory, e.g. <code>C:\PathToMaven2</code>.
			</p>
			<p>
				Refer to the <strong>readme.txt</strong> in the root directory of your Maven 2 Installation.<br/>
				Please ensure that
				<ol>
					<li>JAVA_HOME is set and is pointing to the correct SDK (type java -version to test it)</li>
					<li>The Maven Bin Directory is in your <code>PATH</code> variable</li>
				</ol>
			</p>
		</section>
		<a name="firebird-install"/>
        <section name="Firebird Installation and Configuration">
			<p>
				Firebird can be downloaded from the <a href="http://www.firebirdsql.org/">Firebird Site</a><br/>
				Please choose the installer method. This makes things easier for you. Just follow the onscreen instructions.
			</p>
			<p>
				A nice admin tool for firbird databases can be downloaded from the <a href="http://www.sqlmanager.net/de/products/ibfb/manager">SQL Manager Site</a><br/>
				Just install it using the onscreen instructions.
			</p>
			First of all you have to set up your own Server. Therefore you have to register a new host.<br/>
			A shortcut is also available by pressing <code>SHIFT+CTRL+R</code>.
			<p/>
			Just change the following standard settings:
			<ol>
				<li>Protocol: TCP/IP</li>
				<li>Password: masterkey</li>
			</ol>
			Click 'next' to continue. The other settings should just be left to the standard entries.
			<p/>
			After you set up the server you have to set up the databases to get thing work. Doubleclick on the new host entry in the naigation area situated on your left.
			<ul>
				<li>openuss30.fdb - The Application Database</li>
				<li>openuss30-test.fdb - The Test Database</li>
			</ul>
			Please choose 'Create a new database' from the menu. Unfortunatley there is no shortcut available for this one.
			The host name is your just generated server. It should allready be selected. Click 'Next'.<br/>
			In the database path enter the full qualified path and file name of the database to be created, e.g. 
			<code>C:\DATABASES\openuss30.fdb</code>. <br/>
			Change the <code>SQL Dialect</code> from 1 to <strong>3</strong>.<br/>
			Leave all other settings to the standard ones and click 'Next'.
			A SQL excerpt will be presented to you. Just click 'Finish'.
			<p/><br/>
			<strong>Please repeat these steps for the test database naming it openuss30-test.fdb.</strong>
			<div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
		</section>
		<a name="eclipse-download"/>
        <section name="Download Eclipse 3.2 Callisto">
			<p>
				Just download the <a href="http://teamopenuss.uni-muenster.de/downloads/eclipse-3.2.zip">preconfigured eclipse version</a> and unzip it to your harddisk.
			</p>
			<p>
				After you unziped eclipse go to the <a href="http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/download">Exadel Studio Site</a> and download the free version <code>Exadel Studio 4.0</code>. 
				After the download please follow the onscreen instructions to install it. 
			</p>
			<div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
		</section>

		<a name="maven-repo"/>
        <section name="Set up your Maven2 Repository">
			<p>
				Go to your Maven 2 Root  Directory. Edit the <code>conf/settings.xml</code> with a text editor of your choice.
				Go to the following entry, uncomment it and point it to a path on your harddisk, e.g. <code>c:\Maven2\Repository</code>.
				<source>
					<![CDATA[
<localRepository>C:/MyPathToMyRepository</localRepository>
					]]>
				</source>
			</p>
			<p>
				In order to tell eclipse, where to find the additional libraries, you have to set up a eclipse system variable pointing to your local repository.
				In order to do so, go to the command shell and type 
				<source>
					<![CDATA[
mvn -Declipse.workspace=<path-to-eclipse-workspace> eclipse:add-maven-repo
					]]>
				</source>
				where the 'path-to-eclipse-workspace' is the path to your local workspace of eclipse. If you do not have one, you have to start eclipse before in order to create one.
				Maven then will create a class variable using the entry in the <code>settings.xml</code>. If the does not work you have to create the class variable by yourself.
			</p>
			
			<p>
				In order to be able to use the ant build scripts you have to set up an eclipse ant property <code>m2_repo</code> pointing to your local repository.
				You can define such a property in the eclipse preferences (Ant/Runtimes/Properties).
			</p>
			<div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
		</section>
		
		
		<section name="Nearly finished">
			<p>
				Please use your eclipse to download the sources via <code>CVS</code> form our <a href="source-repository.html">sourceforge.net project site</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				After download has finnished, open the java perspective and open the ant file <code>openuss-plexus/tools/missing-dependencies/build.xml</code> and 
				execute the default target. <br/>
				After build has finnished go to the main ant file <code>openuss-plexus/build.xml</code> and run the install target.
			</p>
			If you discover any problems blease refer to your <a href="troubleshooting.html">troobleshooting page</a> first.
			<div align="right"><a href="#top">Go to the top.</a></div>
		</section>
    </body>
</document>
